danceworld.ie 2018-10-08

# Privacy and Cookie Policy | Danceworld

##### DATA CONTROLLER AND OWNER

Danceworld, 16 Sandford Road, Ranelagh, Dublin 6

Owner contact email: [info@danceworld.ie](mailto:info@danceworld.ie)

##### TYPES OF DATA COLLECTED

Among the types of Personal Data that this Application collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookies, Usage Data and email address. 

Other Personal Data collected may be described in other sections of this privacy policy or by dedicated explanation text contextually with the Data collection. The Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or collected automatically when using this Application. Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools – by this Application or by the owners of third party services used by this Application, unless stated otherwise, serves to identify Users and remember their preferences, for the sole purpose of providing the service required by the User. Failure to provide certain Personal Data may make it impossible for this Application to provide its services.

##### MODE AND PLACE OF PROCESSING THE DATA

**Methods of processing**   
The Data Controller processes the Data of Users in a proper manner and shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorised destruction of the Data. The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organisational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Data Controller, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of the site (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Data Controller at any time.

 **Place**   
The Data is processed at the Data Controller’s operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved with the processing are located. For further information, please contact the Data Controller. 

**Retention time**   
The Data is kept for the time necessary to provide the service requested by the User, or stated by the purposes outlined in this document, and the User can always request that the Data Controller suspend or remove the data. 

**The use of the collected Data**   
The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its services, as well as for the following purposes: 

Analytics, Interaction with data collection platforms and other third parties and Remarketing and behavioral targeting. The Personal Data used for each purpose is outlined in the specific sections of this document.

##### DETAILED INFORMATION ON THE PROCESSING OF PERSONAL DATA

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services: 

**Analytics**   
The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyse web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behaviour. 

**Google Analytics (Google Inc.)**   
Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilises the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Application, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network. Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: US – Privacy Policy – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)

 **Interaction with data collection platforms and other third parties**   
This type of service allows Users to interact with data collection platforms or other services directly from the pages of this Application for the purpose of saving and reusing data. If one of these services is installed, it may collect browsing and Usage Data in the pages where it is installed, even if the Users do not actively use the service.

 **Infusionsoft**  
Infusionsoft Personal Data: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.infusionsoft.com/legal/privacy-policy)

 **Remarketing and behavioural targeting**   
This type of service allows this Application and its partners to inform, optimise and serve advertising based on past use of this Application by the User. This activity is performed by tracking Usage Data and by using Cookies, information that is transferred to the partners that manage the remarketing and behavioural targeting activity. In addition to any opt out offered by any of the services below, the User may opt out of a third-party service’s use of cookies by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page.

 **AdWords Remarketing (Google Inc.)**  
AdWords Remarketing is a remarketing and behavioural targeting service provided by Google Inc. that connects the activity of this Application with the Adwords advertising network and the Doubleclick Cookie. Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. Place of processing: US – Privacy Policy – Opt Out

##### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION ABOUT DATA COLLECTION AND PROCESSING

**Legal action**   
The User’s Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Data Controller, in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of this Application or the related services. The User declares to be aware that the Data Controller may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities. 

**Additional information about User’s Personal Data**   
In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, this Application may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request. System logs and maintenance For operation and maintenance purposes, this Application and any third party services may collect files that record interaction with this Application (System logs) or use for this purpose other Personal Data (such as IP Address).

 **Information not contained in this policy**   
More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Data Controller at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document. The rights of Users Users have the right, at any time, to know whether their Personal Data has been stored and can consult the Data Controller to learn about their contents and origin, to verify their accuracy or to ask for them to be supplemented, cancelled, updated or corrected, or for their transformation into anonymous format or to block any data held in violation of the law, as well as to oppose their treatment for any and all legitimate reasons. Requests should be sent to the Data Controller at the contact information set out above. This Application does not support “Do Not Track” requests. To determine whether any of the third party services it uses honour the “Do Not Track” requests, please read their privacy policies.

 **Changes to this privacy policy**   
The Data Controller reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom. If a User objects to any of the changes to the Policy, the User must cease using this Application and can request that the Data Controller remove the Personal Data. Unless stated otherwise, the then-current privacy policy applies to all Personal Data the Data Controller has about Users. 

**Information about this privacy policy**   
The Data Controller is responsible for this privacy policy.

##### COOKIE POLICY

**How we use cookies**  
The following tables describe the cookies we use on this site and what we use them for. Currently we operate an ‘implied consent’ policy which means that we assume you are happy with this usage. If you are not happy, then you should either not use this site, or you should delete www.danceworld.ie cookies having visited the site, or you should browse the site using your browser’s anonymous usage setting (called “Incognito” in Chrome, “InPrivate” for Internet Explorer, "Private Browsing" in Firefox and Safari etc).

 **Session Cookies**  
We use session cookies to remember your log-in and what you’ve put in the shopping basket. These we deem strictly necessary to the working of the website. If these are disabled then various functionality on the site will be broken. More information on session cookies and what they are used for at http://www.allaboutcookies.org/cookies/session-cookies-used-for.html. 

**Cookie Name** | **Purpose**  
---|---  
**PHPSESSID** | This cookie is used to hold the unique session ID which is generated every time our site is visited. This cookie is deleted when you close the browser. ****  
**Session_ID** | This retains your ID for your shopping basket. Without this cookie, you cannot add products to your basket or make any purchases.  
  
**Cookies for Site Analytics**

**Provider** | **Cookie name** | **Expires** | **Purpose** | **More information**  
---|---|---|---|---  
Google Analytics | _utma | 2 years | This cookie is typically written to the browser upon the first visit to your site _from that web browser_. If the cookie has been deleted by the browser operator, and the browser subsequently visits your site, a new __utma cookie is written with a different unique ID. This cookie is used to determine unique visitors to your site and it is updated with each page view. Additionally, this cookie is provided with a unique ID that Google Analytics uses to ensure both the validity and accessibility of the cookie as an extra security measure. | [Read Google Analytics Safeguarding your data](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)  
Google Analytics | _utmb _utmc | 30 minutes | These cookies work in tandem to calculate visit length. Google __utmb cookie demarks the exact arrival time, then Google __utmc registers the precise exit time of the user. | [Read Google Analytics Safeguarding your data](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)  
Google Analytics | _utmz | 6 months | This cookie stores the type of referral used by the visitor to reach your site, whether via a direct method, a referring link, a website search, or a campaign such as an ad or an email link. It is used to calculate search engine traffic, ad campaigns and page navigation within your own site. The cookie is updated with each page view to your site. | [Read Google Analytics Safeguarding your data](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)  
Google Analytics | _utmv | 2 years | This cookie is not normally present in a default configuration of the tracking code. The __utmv cookie passes the information provided via the [_setVar()](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/gajs/methods/gaJSApiBasicConfiguration#_gat.GA_Tracker_._setVar) method, which you use to create a custom user segment. This string is then passed to the Analytics servers in the GIF request URL via the utmcc parameter. This cookie is only written if you have added the _setVar() method for the tracking code on your website page. | [Read Google Analytics Safeguarding your data](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)  
Google Analytics | _utmx | 2 years | This cookie is used by Website Optimizer and only set when the Website Optimizer tracking code is installed and correctly configured for your pages. When the optimizer script executes, this cookie stores the variation this visitor is assigned to for each experiment, so the visitor has a consistent experience on your site.  See the [Website Optimizer Help Center](http://www.google.com/support/websiteoptimizer/) for more information. | [Read Google Analytics Safeguarding your data](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)  
  
**  
**Personal Data (or Data)**   
**Any information regarding a natural person, a legal person, an institution or an association, which is, or can be, identified, even indirectly, by reference to any other information, including a personal identification number. **

**Usage Data**

** Information collected automatically from this Application (or third party services employed in this Application), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilised by the Users who use this Application, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilised to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server’s answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilised by the User, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the Application) and the details about the path followed within the Application with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User’s IT environment. **

 **User**

** The individual using this Application, which must coincide with or be authorised by the Data Subject, to whom the Personal Data refers.   
**  
**Data Subject**   
**The legal or natural person to whom the Personal Data refers. Data Processor (or Data Supervisor) The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organisation authorised by the Data Controller to process the Personal Data in compliance with this privacy policy. **

**Data Controller (or Owner)**

** The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organisation with the right, also jointly with another Data Controller, to make decisions regarding the purposes, and the methods of processing of Personal Data and the means used, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of this Application. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified, is the Owner of this Application. **

**This Application**

** The hardware or software tool by which the Personal Data of the User is collected. **

**Cookies**

** Small piece of data stored in the User’s device. **

**Legal information**

** Notice to European Users: this privacy statement has been prepared in fulfilment of the obligations under Art. 10 of EC Directive n. 95/46/EC, and under the provisions of Directive 2002/58/EC, as revised by Directive 2009/136/EC, on the subject of Cookies.   
This privacy policy relates solely to this Application
